JACK SENECHAL

Located in Kentfield, CA Phone: 415-779-2701

Email: jacksenechal@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/jacksenechal

INTRODUCTION

My ideal workplace has a vibrant environment of innovation, a strong team practicing Agile methodologies, and a culture of excellence. It is more than a day job, it is a platform to launch big ideas. I bring 10 years of industry experience, an appetite for challenges, and a broad understanding of the technological landscape.

I am an engineer with a passion for humanity. I wish to build lucid technology to help navigate the rapid changes lying ahead. To that end I have a deep interest in architecture of <u>emergent systems</u>, open infrastructure, and tools that facilitate collaboration, communication, and education. I value foresight, innovation, multidimensional thinking, and appropriate application of technology. I am existentially intolerant of the status quo.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Programming experience with **Ruby**, Rails, **JavaScript**, CoffeeScript, **Node.js**, jQuery, D3, PHP, ActionScript, Flex, and SuperCollider. Limited experience with C/C++, Java, Perl and Python.

My ideal development environment is Vim on Linux.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Independent Contractor 2004 - 2014

- Pegg (July 2014 current). Mobile game development in JavaScript and Parse with a Famo.us front-end and a Flux architecture. Authoring an express/JS admin interface. Major refactoring around CommonJS Promises.
- Darasha (April 2014 June 2014). Rapid prototyping of global-graph technologies using XDI and Famo.us. Integration of XDI with Ruby on Rails applications. Launched beta cloud name service based on XDI and Node.js.
- <u>Superluminal Systems</u> (August 2013 January 2014). Helped to develop and launch the first client site based on the Superluminal Learning Management System. Collaborated on innovative user interface elements using D3 and CoffeeScript. Wordpress plugin wrangling, development and customization.
- Turnbull & Asser shirtmakers (2008-2009). Built a virtual showroom for their bespoke

- department, allowing users to browse fabrics and place orders. Ruby on Rails backend, Flash frontend.
- <u>Idance.net</u> video dance instruction (2004-2005). Designed and implemented an e-commerce site in PHP and MySQL. Pay-per-download purchasing, content browsing and searching, backend for the client to manage the site with detailed admin reports on purchases and user activity.
- Various smaller websites and components.

Founder, OpenTest Pro, LLC - 2008 - 2011

- Founded the company to provide educational resources relating to automated testing and continuous integration using open source tools in a PHP environment.
- Activities include technical writing, web application development in Ruby on Rails and Flex, studio voiceover recording, and project management.

Web Developer, OnForce, Inc - New York, NY June 2006 - December 2007

- Programmed features and updates to the OnForce platform.
- Introduced automated testing with PHPUnit. Implemented tests for OnForce's public-facing API.
 Unit testing infrastructure included PHPUnit with a custom test database refreshing mechanism,
 Selenium, and CruiseControl.
- Integrated OnFoce platform with Salesforce APIs to provide up-to-date customer information for sales and support teams.
- Project managed the implementation of Salesforce throughout the company, and oversaw the administration of the application.

Development Lead, JBA Network - Asheville, NC June 2003 - December 2006

- Project manager and lead programmer for medium-scale web application,
 mynewsletterbuilder.com. Designed the application and coded the initial release. Later oversaw
 the ongoing development team for the project. MNB remains one of the primary revenue
 sources for the company.
- Developed a modular, evented, MVC programming framework for PHP.
- Concept development, project management, and programming for other company products and services, including www.jukeboxalive.com and www.byregion.net.
- Systems administration and networking (Linux, Windows).

Intern, US Navy FNMOD - Asheville, NC May 2001 - August 2001

Programmer, database designer for the Fleet Numerical Meteorology and Oceanography
Detachment. Migrated Navy weather data from a flat text format to a MySQL database. Wrote a
Java application for quality checking weather data, and converting it to a MySQL-accessible
format.

Geek in Residence, Internet Safety Association - Asheville, NC December 1998 - December 1999

• HTML and JavaScript programming, graphic design, web design and management, network management, computer maintenance.

Various - Asheville, NC 1996 - 1998

 Assorted computer related jobs and volunteer work, including CAT-5 and fiber-optic network installation, web development, desktop publishing, technical writing, computer repair, and technical support.

VOLUNTEER

Clairvision School of Meditation (Nonprofit) - 1999 - 2014

- Overhauled e-commerce and fulfillment systems, reducing order processing time by a factor of 10. Created shipping and fulfillment application using data from the existing system and presenting it in an intuitive interface for volunteers to process orders, pack items, and print postage-paid shipping labels. Application written in JavaScript with a Ruby backend, using APIs from Stripe and EasyPost. (2013-2014)
- Developing electronic music systems using open source tools. Trained a team of musicians in basic programming. Wrote arpeggiator and sampler patches for SuperCollider. Prototyped Reactable clone in PureData. (2011)
- Developed Java search engine for knowledge base, website development including JavaScript shipping estimator. (2000)

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Enlightened Structure

- Co-founded the Enlightened Structure metaproject to create an open, decentralized, collaborative application and data ecosystem.
- Envisioning and prototyping of tools and applications such as reputation exchange, forking-based collaboration, and visualization and navigation of the global semantic graph.
- Research and synthesis of information on candidate technologies.
- Code contributions to related projects (primarily written in Ruby and JavaScript).

Skype Links Chrome Extension

- A Chrome extension that uses customizable pattern matching to extract phone numbers from web pages and convert them to skype: or callto: links.
- 47,000 users, 4 stars, 900 g+ plus ones.

COMMUNITIES AND CONFERENCES

- Building the Collaborative Internet
- Indie Web Camp
- Internet Identity Workshop

EDUCATION

BA in mathematics, minor in computer science from the <u>University of North Carolina at Asheville</u> (May, 2003)